A Guide to the Henry J. Dekker Papers, 1949-2009
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Henry J. Dekker Papers, 1949-2009
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2012-055
1.8 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The collection consists of papers relating to Henry Dekker's tenure as rector of Board of Visitors, service on Pamplin Advisory Council, interest in Pamplin College of Business, and the history of Virginia Tech.
Dekker, Henry J.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Henry J. Dekker Papers were donated to Special Collections in August 2010 and June 2012.
Biographical Information
Henry J. Dekker served on the board of visitors from 1989 to 1997, and was rector from 1996 to 1997. He was also a longtime member of the Pamplin Advisory Council. More information about him can be found on the university website; under the history of Virginia Tech administration - Board of Visitors.
Scope and Content
Included in the collection are papers relating to Henry J. Dekker's tenure as rector of Board of Visitors, service on Pamplin Advisory Council, and interest in Pamplin College of Business. Papers include, but are not limited to, education material, university development material, minutes, correspondence with the President, council material, major gifts campaign, publications, director dividends, correspondence with the Dean, College of Education material, VT Foundation material, VT magazine, campaign for Virginia Tech material, university plan, model land grant university material, land grant material, comparisons of tuition and fees, education statistics, programs and reports, photographs and newspaper clippings, as well as an interview with Dr. Newman.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by the subject, and includes an audio cassette tape in Box 2.
Index Terms
Persons:
Newman, Walter S., (Walter Stephenson), 1895-1947
Corporate Names:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. Board of Visitors.
Subjects:
University Archives; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University. College of Business.
Contents List
- Board of Visitors: Education Material (Box-folder 1-1)
- Board of Visitors: University Development (Box-folder 1-2)
- Board of Visitors: Minutes (Box-folder 1-3)
- Board of Visitors: Correspondence with the President (Box-folder 1-4)
- Virginia Business Higher Education Council (2 folders) (Box-folder 1-5 to 1-6)
- Pamplin College of Business: Major Gifts Campaign (Box-folder 1-7)
- Pamplin College of Business: Advisory Council (Box-folder 1-8)
- Pamplin College of Business: Publications (Box-folder 1-9)
- Pamplin College of Business: Director Dividends (2 folders) (Box-folder 1-10 to 1-11)
- Pamplin College of Business: Correspondence with the Dean (Box-folder 1-12)
- College of Education (Box-folder 1-13)
- Virginia Tech Foundation (Box-folder 1-14)
- Virginia Tech Magazine (Box-folder 1-15)
- Campaign for Virginia Tech (Box-folder 1-16)
- University Plan (Box-folder 1-17)
- Model Land Grant University (Box-folder 1-18)
- Land Grant Material (Box-folder 1-19)
- Comparison Tuition and Fees (Box-folder 1-20)
- Education Statistics (Box-folder 1-21)
- Programs and Reports (Box-folder 1-22)
- Photographs and Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 1-23)
- The Family Tree by Mary Preston Gray (2 folders), 1980 (Box-folder 2-1 to 2-2)
- Newman Inauguration Material, 1949 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1940s-1980s (Box-folder 2-4)
- Newspaper Clippings on Newman, 1940s-1980s (Box-folder 2-5)
- Pamplin Pamphlet, McComas Inauguration, and Poem, 1989, 2009, n.d. (Box-folder 2-6)
- Center for European Studies and Architecture (Box-folder 2-7)
- Founder's Week Material, 1997 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Handwritten Reception Plans, 1947, 1951, n.d. (Box-folder 2-9)
- Newman Interview (audio cassette tape), 1968 (Box-folder 2-10)